//creating an array and passing question qNumber, questions, options and corrects
let questions = [
    {
        qNum : 1,
        question: "Which 19th-century Italian composer and violinist was known as \"The Devil's Violinist\"?",
        options: [
            "Antonio Vivaldi",
            "Antonio Salieri",
            "Niccolò Paganini",
            "Gioachino Rossini",
        ],
        correct: "Niccolò Paganini",
    },
    {
        qNum : 2,
        question: "How many musical periods are typically studied?",
        options: [
            "6",
            "3",
            "7",
            "4",
        ],
        correct: "6",
    },
    {
        qNum : 3,
        question: "Who composed 'The Flying Dutchman'?",       
        options: [
            "Richard Wagner",
            "Mozart",
            "Robert Schumann",
            "Giuseppe Verdi",
        ],
        correct: "Richard Wagner",
    },
    {
        qNum : 4,
        question: "Which composer of the Classical period is considered both the Father of the Symphony as well as the Father of the String Quartet?",       
        options: [
            "Josef Haydn",
            "Johann Hummel",
            "Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart",
            "Franz Schubert",
        ],
        correct: "Josef Haydn",
    },
    {
        qNum : 5,
        question: "What is the first note of a scale called?",        
        options: [
            "bottom",
            "root",
            "tonic",
            "variable",
        ],
        correct: "tonic",
    },
    {
        qNum : 6,
        question: "Which of these bands was led by a singer from Africa?",        
        options: [
            "the Who",
            "the Beatles",
            "Queen",
            "Jonas Brothers",
        ],
        correct: "Queen",
    },
    {
        qNum : 7,
        question: "In Greek methodology, from what was the first lyre constructed?",        
        options: [
            "a turtle shell",
            "thin air",
            "twings and resin",
            "a gourd",
        ],
        correct: "a turtle shell",
    },
    {
        qNum : 8,
        question: "Which  of the following instruments does not employ values to change pitch?",        
        options: [
            "flute",
            "flugelhorn",
            "trumpet",
            "trombone",
        ],
        correct: "trombone",
    },
    {
        qNum : 9,
        question: "Who was known as the \"King of Swing\"?",        
        options: [
            "Benny Goodman",
            "Elvis Presley",
            "Gene Krupa",
            "Louis Armstrong",
        ],
        correct: "Benny Goodman",
    },
    {
        qNum : 10,
        question: "What was the name of the Who's second rock opera?",        
        options: [
            "Hari",
            "All that jazz",
            "Quadrophenia",
            "Pat Garrett and Billy the KqNum",
        ],
        correct: "Quadrophenia",
    },
];